# Stephen M. Coakley

## Software Developer

me@stephencoakley.com (608) 371-7841 github.com/sagebind

I am a passionate full-stack software developer experienced with a wide variety of systems and technologies, specializing in distributed web applications. I also have an advanced understanding of systems programming, concurrency, and asynchronous programming that provide a deeper understanding of the software stack from end to end.

As an open-source advocate, I contribute to open-source projects regularly, and have created dozens of my own side projects that I work on in my spare time.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Widen Enterprises, Inc — Madison, WI

**Software Developer** June 2016 - Present

- Creating distributed back-end microservices in Java to power existing and new web-based products that serve over 40 million requests per day.
- Re-designing existing architecture to be more efficient and parallel in order to improve overall performance and stability and to support a growing customer base.
- Technologies used include Java, MySQL, NGINX, Docker, and Kubernetes.

#### University of Wisconsin-Whitewater — Whitewater, WI

**Computer Science Peer Tutor** 

Sept 2014 - May 2016

• Worked for the Computer Science department in a small team of peer tutors. Provided walk-in tutoring for students where I would give ad-hoc lessons to help give a clearer understanding of course concepts. Subjects taught included C, assembly, AI, and computer science theory.

**Undergraduate Research Assistant** 

Sept 2013 - May 2014

• Developed a Microsoft Word plugin using C# to embed revision control inside Word documents.

### **PROJECTS**

Riptide May 2017 - Present

- Dynamically typed, expression based programming language aimed at replacing POSIX shell.
   Interpreter written in Rust.
- github.com/sagebind/riptide

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Wisconsin-Whitewater**

Sept 2013 - May 2016

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Computer Science Major/Cumulative GPA: 3.909 / 3.891

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

## **Version-Aware Word Documents**

Stephen M. Coakley, Jacob Mischka, and Cheng Thao. 2014. Version-Aware Word Documents.

In Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on (Document) Changes: modeling, detection, storage and visualization (DChanges '14).

ACM, New York, NY, USA, Article 2, 4 pages.

DOI=10.1145/2723147.2723152